# **ERIK KIMSEY**

### // SOFTWARE ENGINEER

### erikkimsey.com

T: 540 278 4525 E: kimseyerik@gmail.com

github.com/erikkimsey linkedin.com/in/erikkimsey As a creative technologist and software engineer, I find the best tools and architecture for the job. Experimentation and breadth of experience are at my core. I strive for resuability, modularity, and succinctness. My passions lay in building intuitive, performant, innovative, and beautiful technology. As a full-stack engineer, my focus is mobile-web using JavaScript (ES6/7), React, NodeJS, and Web APIs.

### SKILLS

### **Full-Stack Engineering**

- JavaScript, React, NextJS
- Redux
- CSS3 / Sass / CSS-in-JS
- HTML5
- NodeJS / Express
- Relational & NoSQL DBs
- GraphQL
- Apollo-Server / -Client
- Python / Django
- Webpack
- Test-Driven Development
- Bootstrap 4
- Web Audio, Web Sensor APIs
- P5.js, D3.js,
- Angular

### Languages

- Javascript (ES6/7)
- Python
- SQL
- GraphQL
- Java (Android)
- Processing
- C/C++

### **Design Tools**

- Adobe Illustrator
- Adobe Photoshop
- Adobe InDesign
- Adobe XD

### Misc. Technology

- React-Native
- Android SDK
- **ARCore**
- Propellerhead Reason
- Abelton Live
- Audacity
- Blender
- Unity3D
- JUCE Arduino / IC
- Adobe Premiere
- Adobe AfterEffects

## WORK EXPERIENCE

#### 9/2018

#### **NEXTLEVEL / KARDION**

### Front-End Engineer

### (HTML5, Sass, Bootstrap)

Per design specifications, helped build responsive website for medtech firm. Kardion GmbH

#### 6/2018

### **NEXTLEVEL / B612 DESIGN**

#### Front-End Engineer

### (Angular 4 & D3)

Contributed to the development of an interactive guilloche for use by a Stuttgart design firm, B612

#### 1/2018

### **RAINCROW**

### **Back-End Engineer**

### (NodeJS & Redis)

Contributed to the early-stage engineering of a Node server and Redis database supporting the activity of a MMORPG (Covens)

### 10/2016 - 6/2017 **CHARTIQ**

### JavaScript Engineer

### (JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, & AngularJS)

- Helped implement "ProCharts" in a ChartIQ client's application
- Contributed to performance upgrades, using JavaScript, to ChartIQ's flagship financial-charting
- Contributed to public-facing documentation

### 2012 - 2016

### **ROSETTA STONE**

### Studio Recording Technician/ **Product Support**

- Monitored and recorded Live Studio Sessions.
- Created training materials for Studio Recording Technician role.
- Helped consumers troubleshoot Rosetta Stone software issues

# EDUCATION

### 2018 - 2019

### **COMPUTER SCIENCE**

Lambda School

Curriculum:

- Full-Stack Web Development
- Database and RESTful API Design
- Programming paradigms (Declarative, Imperative, and Procedural)
- Software Design Patterns
- Single-Page Application Development
- Algorithm Analysis
- **Data Structures**
- Theory of Computation
- Computer Architecture
- Cellular Automata
- Version Control
- Agile (Scrum and Kanban) and Waterfall techniques

### 8/2017 - 12/2017 **COMPUTER SCIENCE**

### OSU

- Object-Oriented Programming in C++
- Discrete Maths

### **WEB DESIGN & DEVELOPMENT (CERT)**

Blue Ridge Community College

- Javascript, HTML, CSS, Java
- **Graphic Design Concepts**
- Adobe Illustrator, Photoshop, InDesign

### 2006 - 2010 PHILOSOPHY (BS)

James Madison University

Phi Sigma Tau Philosophy Honors Society Member

Minors: creative writing & design